你好歡迎來到active書本流
第 1 條 .2
是二月十五日，二零二三。
歡迎來到 Active Inference
我們是一個參與式的線上研究院
傳達學習的研究院
且練習應用主動推理
這是錄製於存檔直播流中
所以請提供我們 feedback 給我們
可以提升我們的工作
所有背景和观点都是
歡迎 請看 下一 頻道 觀看
livestreaming禮儀
看喔
activeinference.org加入互动
直播和其它项目
藍色給你
great well this is our second discussion
書binding 經常性的 governing
我們在此，變革從此開始
討論第二本教科書的部分
所以我想我們可能要繞一圈
我是藍騎士，介紹自己
獨立研究顧問兼
新墨西哥和我將把它轉交給
譙宇特
我是Tyler，我是一個協定設計師
且加州DOW研究者說
到丹尼爾
我是一名加州的研究者且過
它是讓娜
明顯 是 一位 真正 的 作者 来了
更多從實用側面的
世界一直在擔任董事之職
最終的に強烈な関心を持つ
在理論和受到启发的
自由能最小化
那原則採用並應用到
企業治理的世界
因此我非常 appreciate這本書
你今天邀我來啊和
希望能夠再次參與
stimulating討論我總是愛到
看如何
你 知道 有 那么 多 工作 哦
寫書去了它是很
孤獨的旅程當它們離去時
你看實際上有這樣 talented 組團
看著它讀它
critiques 它 并 參與
a dialogue it's a great gift for an
我作者所以我非常非常高興能夠
謝謝
超級好哇
傳承它藍
所以我們在此討論第二部分
自由能治理如此過往
四週我們討論過這些最後
四章
嗯 和今天要討論的
只涵蓋那些部分
所以一個路綫圖我們 uh 有了一些
kind of category questions uh regarding
共情與自由能量的角色
治理人工的角色
自由能治理中的智能
and also on Duality management
從同理心開始我們就
這裡
所以 我 似乎 是
往上查找照片以便從上方查看
umu 交流 和和 如如 在
我的照片滑動我發現這張舊的
右來自
um and and it's about
情緒感同身受
圖像並且它有感知行動
耦合與共用表徵和
像是自我與其他者
不知道
你已經讀過這篇papers但對我而言
像是某個看起來像圖形的
包羅了這些我們所
一直在書中談論的
umu 和 所以 用 Bijan 的書 語
認知的形式為世界
enactment 是目的導向的
行動為中心且社會建構
的與
期待基於於
理解一個企業的環境
是環境參與的事宜
在互動揭露的形式中
意義重大和分配機率
到一個外在未知的有限集合中
狀態
我和我只是在想關於
可能是同理心在_like_的角色
獲得共用表象或
共用
理解所以我不太知道你
想要轉到下一頁
嗯 和 所謂 的 此處 需要 源情
為此共用意義和共用
期待著且好奇想知道
你對此有何想法可能？
或是我可能知道我們也聽到了
很多關於情緒的角色
商界成功中的智能
where does maybe emotional intelligence
來到自由能治理_like它
那是嗎
um 也重要嗎 或者是你的
理論 好了 我現在認為 是
很好問題首先我做了
我不曾遇過這篇papers我想是
一個精彩的說明說過
看來很有趣看到它放
感知然後行動 我把它放在
從另一個方向我看行動是
真的決定我們的感知
但我是啊
我認為這是個非常好的問題
因為你所做的是你
打開某事物我認為是部分
我工作的黑箱
因為當你看著
我知道 我不太喜歡 很底的
think I said this in one of our previous
我偏好討論前線工作人員
人士 真的 在 前線
having said this the the top down
-up 动态 在每個有
層級和有效率地
sometimes是怎麼樣
literally 工作 一起 所以 然後 你 打開
揭開合作黑箱的
um how do you how do you engage actually
如何你才能理解每個
那是同理心的地方其他和我認為
扮演很重要的角色我想
那是哪裡
人類在情感智能開始
扮演了非常重要的角色我
已完成
為書的目的為的
目的的自由能治理
我專注的概念真的很強烈
通訊
但溝通中有許多
那是也與同理心有關你也可以
爭論
讓確保實際上
people hear what you're saying uh and
當然sometimes 有些時候需要
成為一個同理心的維度在其中
這是我想的
那瀑布就在這裡
你開始有目的時就從這裡開始
沒有目的則成為了
有點 모호하지만
very clear that we want to go to Rome
then there's many ways that are leading
錯但你繼續
旅程並保持團體
一起保持團隊活力
動機為經歷許多
跨越阿爾卑斯山區的危險 maybe 正在 出現
從歐洲到你這裡再到
羅馬
um communication becomes very essential
當你從實用的角度看
工作的研究即使你把它拿走
像有生意一樣要有評論
在我看來，這是一種
領導企業雜誌中的
處理目前管理上的真正問題
公司領導層包括前線
勞工們正著眼於且你看見那
同理心情感智能和
通信真的很重要
在制定最複雜的策略中
因為沒有意義才工作
very聰明地分析
世界去向何方如果你不在
能對齊並激勵所有
所有智能的所有細點都資源
在 The Firm 加入這所以我留下了
離開作為現在工作的一部分
進入
微觀層面的溝通是什麼
between
你知道  lets say 風雲再起 和 一個
前線 Worker 你有多少同理心
在某些情況下展示以確保
那是整個流程其實是會去
思考以回答我所工作的想法
看情緒的答案
聴察時之智能
有你會考慮的維度
更多在細節方面的方式事物
正在被轉譯，我選擇離開
從且Really考慮它作為一種黑
box of how
可能
通訊最好在非常
specifics
所以就清楚了因為這是
非常不尋常我想這是很好的
因為這是問題
深深觸動管理的心
um 和 已經 显著 團結 在 近期
多年來非常受歡迎的主題
沒有人曾問過我那話
這個上下文中問題在於我真的很
appreciation 你
記憶得起，嗯
我不確定你是否已閱讀
法國就像是一個非常
first papers that we did at the
在直播中我們會介紹這個研究院
知道還是溝通就像一樣
必要工具以及溝通是如何
用來 kinda 創立那那
共享意義念與共識期望
關於具體的細節
它是還是
um oh and then we didn't we did another
近期論文處理溝通
像是主動推理類似
跟隨但由不同作者寫的一篇
記住它的名字那是
有趣的事情我會真的
appreciate if you could send me the
到那些文獻
回看直播如果 uh 我
記不起來
感謝你我很 appreciative
和  只是 創意 想要 知道 你 是否 认為
人在認知上有我們有
同理心在人類認知中的作用
扮演你認為是否有角色存在
一個在組織認知中的類比
知覺到其中有什麼
這是什麼樣的角色會相對應到来
可能是有點玄妙或什麼
你那有何想法
沒有 我認為 uh
你知道我指的是什麼 一個公司是怎樣的
法團是一個法律虛構，它是
really a bunch of people and a bunch of
而且sometimes實際上只有
可能是說在一群
業務中沒有{}
機器或任何一樣
認為真的來於
我想這是歸結為 peoples
領導力
它歸結到的是它的身份
至文化止 在近年
你已經看到過許多許多公司我
通過他們的領導者已付出
許多的言詞敬重為
empathetic organization having
為需求而理解
front線戰鬥員的勞工
公司的一項資產所以是這樣
今天認為
我無法想像一家公司會
不是同理心且或未整合
同理心
作為重要的支柱
對於價值觀與文化
它活著，它沒有很好的機會
為了生存當你凝視之時
文化在企業中是什麼
在組織設定中真的是
behavioral 師 標準化
really what we would expect of people in
這是特定設定你知道而且 uh
um and and I and I think this uh uh
今日同理心非常重要
而且我想說的是
共情的概念
有了全新的層面
跟隨疫情你知道當你
開始看到人們被鎖up
having to when you have two working
坐在家裡
突然有很多事情要平衡
前面
Showing 準備 優容 和 護理 对 之 所 爲
非常特別的挑戰人們面對
如果你不
你將最終會失去
sometimes 即使 是 你 最 好 的 人
且只是提出一個問題在
稍微不同的方式，所以已經很多了
我們一直在談論同理心
像是人類個體的_terms_of_like
思考正確而且嗨那應該
是您文化中重要的一部分
因為它允許溝通順暢 flows
內外
但我想知道是否有類似的替代品
組織層級法則：The Firm
如此，在個體的相同方式下
你正複製動態的
另一個外部的人
有人存在一種方式在
組織作為其自身的-entity
鏡射外界，亦自映射
它的自己感知
環境以及你可以稱之為
其他公司或其他
的正在在
環境是相當類似maybe
你認為該公司是如何運作的
under free energy governance is
接收性的
可以整合這些資訊
外部環境 uh 那是嗎
different in a way to how people
傳統上認為是集結
環境的資料
當你實際上看如果的話}
要拆解同理心何為
真的 我認為有兩種
這兩維我就可以
立刻想到你你说
有人 mattered 所以 某人 mattered
其次你尊重那个人
當然你真的
你聽我想聆聽的部分
這是極為重要的一部分如何可以
你要是有同理心就這樣做
聽是為了第一個才聽的所以當你
看這三維的所有事物
尊敬
聽
有人 Somebody 和
說的內容
an essential Foundation of free energy
governance 因為 自由能量
governance 有效說 即使 是
弱訊號蘊藏轉變的
我們需要傾聽的潛力首先
你所需要的，以啟動所有你的感官
in free energy governance
聽前線人員真正所說的
必須要說
和
是工作的假設
他們說什麼很重要
他們提到它
能夠讀到字裡行間
這樣才有意義所以我只能這麼做
拉長概念的維度
同理心並真正連結到
進入自由能量管制
拆解成說穿了就是這三種
什麼是同理心所代表的
然後把它拉回到自由能量
有效的治理框架
說
這是
策略本质上是生成性的
過程
你可表述預測於
頂點但他們只有那麼好是因為你
可以挑戰他們的自下而上的資料
和底部上來的資料來訪問它
讓它
從底部流向頂部大概
需要一種同理心的元素因為
我的個人經驗是越
接近前線越 Close 越近
在組織中
the stronger is actually the resistance
分享有价值的信息
那是因為人們的原因不是那樣
不要分享
因為人們 preferring 不去
伸舌
人們不一定偏好假設
現在對某事的責任
他們說，甚至如果它成為一個project
在自己的份上他們可能必須
執行但他們不會想要
執行以使你發現的是解鎖
對價值的寶貴智能是
組織的前線
這是管理上的另一個挑戰
右 且 我 想 它 要求 非常
強調溝通且確實
需要同理心和同理心和
maybe now I can I can close the circle
here to your question Tyler and what
藍色之前提到過
可能是需要更多
只是一個有同理心的領導者而已
必須信任過程在
我感到自在的整體文化
為此要 functioning 在於 持續
且永續基礎因為當我們
看自由能治理這就是
不是像一個一次性項目這樣
深深嵌入該公司的基因中
說未來企業的關鍵是這樣说
確認我們是否持續
生成性最小化預測誤差
sometimes at the bottom and we want to
挑戰那些預測與
前線情報
所以就隨便追加一個問題 如你剛才
特別是關於像是
疫情和我都在那里
思考著
同理心與領導力
知道 我 只是 回到
正向網路 versus
直接默認模式網路和
所以我想可能同理心就是
中央
um component in the default mode Network
像同理心一樣是 Default Mode 的_default_樣式
網路就像以人為中心的部分
那裡
um and and I was I think like now with
像Jarred我一樣的疫情剛剛打中了我
我們現在好像已經這樣了所以我覺得 ourselves
so off task like I mean maybe not in
每個組織但我認為都是
我們像是更加中心化的社會
我們被翻譯成了DMM上的重型
as opposed to the tpn uh just just
因為文化上因為的更大的
everyone的同理心程度都只是
必須要為人潮來的人們打擊節奏
和
他們的環境調整正確
我認為這 reinforcement 它的
這是看事情非常好的方式实际上
在特定任務的網路
或在Default模式的Network中你
是絕對正確，同理心是其中一部分
現在你看時的預設模式
它是關於 Defaults 的一切 呢意思是
因為如此多的痛苦如此多
tragedies 確實 在第一波中
不确定性與可預測性在
我們的模型被 overwhelms 因為 我們
世界模型未準備好要面對
這花了整整一年
和整合了
完美地適應調整到一個
更進化模型並發展
新的處理方式如何做
但其中一個元素例如是家
辦公室當你想到有多困難
它是許多公司成為很多人的目標
人們回办公室去而且你可以
差不多說是辦公室 maybe
專用任務網路
你知道你去因為你真的很
執行特定任務在裡
建好然後你就離開它然後
你知道你已經不在了所以almost
有個叫link的
腦子在辦公室
任務專屬性
um I do recall another example which is
我不希望離題太遠但我是
記起 banks 引入了
你知道那只是九零年代的事
我想那是他們介紹給你的
可以穿便服
所以通常就是你穿
一套衣服然後你在 Friday 前來
可以穿休閒智能
我记得有人告诉我
当你去金門時
薩克斯交易floor的人是
那可能是 Friday 那天的人
因為他看起來像我
連這市場都不用穿這衣服
很多人說當金融
crisis hit in 2008 and which was really
豪華
把 讓 很 多 人 去
痛苦啊，那真是太糟糕了，还有房贷
那是部分related to的fact
那是
週五 casual 成為almost 相當於
週末隨興且無所事事且
: 影響人們如何
執行他們的任務
他們對風險的態度如此
思考形式與隨和性是否
very very critical aspects of of you
知道一個組織如何運作和
sometimes the informal organization
which is obviously a function of the
formal one
can be much more important and sometimes
it can be much more important how
information is Flowing most of the time
in organizations coming back to the free
energy governance framework
the most valuable information does not
come
through the formal channels it comes
through informal channels it may come
through a conversation at the water
cooler
all these things which are not
necessarily documented in the
traditional forms of corporate
communication so I think these are
probably also the channels where empathy
can be best
communicated and I think the big loss of
um during the pandemic was that while
the the office work and the office space
was maybe very formal and very
um
tasks specific
I think it was at the same time
underestimated how important it is to
provide to frontliners to even to
leaders the source of empathy in
exchange because I think most people
were confronted with the terrible
loneliness and so we shouldn't
underestimate and we shouldn't
Bash Too Much the physical office space
is a very important place not only where
um uh where you perform your task but
could be also a source of of being
energized and receiving understanding
for issues which have nothing to do with
your job and more importantly it's
really the the side of learning I do
recall when Morgan Stanley CEO insisted
that people are coming back to the
office it was really by saying our
future as a company is dependent on
continuing training people and bringing
in young Talent who have to learn on the
job how can they learn on the job when
the office is empty so there is a duty
in the name of firm survival to keep the
firm as a learning side and that means
bringing in the side so that's a long
talk
um obviously the the concept of empathy
in the context of free energy governance
it's not an obvious one but I think this
is an interesting very interesting
conversation and I do think that we um
we need to dissect
the what really empathy means for and
then we need to look at what is a firm a
firm consisting of people of assets but
also of the physical space and I think
the space is a is a very important
Dimension to consider uh and that's
where the pandemic is an interesting
example of how it can be a source of
um of
whatever positive we associate was
empathy to provide
awesome so we'll move now into talking a
little bit more about artificial
intelligence
um and do you say in the book you say in
fact we are challenged not to allow for
the human brain's computational limits
to solely determine perception and sense
making instead Outsourcing some of the
heavy information lifting to the
environment in form of extended
cognition is the essence of optimizing
prediction error minimization the more
exponential and hence discontinuous a
market environment the more we need
self-organizing mechanisms that leverage
the world as a supervisory signal
challenging and circular causality the
very perceptual content of our
predictions
and in reading this I have been having
lots of fun working with GPT chat as I'm
sure you have and many others have have
been um and really as as just kind of a
like a platform or a standing like a
springboard for like where we what we
already know like it's a very big
cognitive synthesis of like you know the
whole internet Circa 2021 or or
something like that and so like this is
really a cognitive extension like our
smartphone and many other things uh um
and so I just was wondering what role
you might see for chat GPT or other
automated artificial intelligence I mean
like the you know there's no limit to
um assist us with free energy governance
because I really see like an assisting
with the synthesis and integration of
information like at a very large scale
even just now compared to a year ago so
do you see a role um for AI in free
energy governance or helping us to kind
of
springboard our leadership platforms
yeah
very good question so let me
um uh there's many dimensions to it
number one
um
free energy governance
strictly speaking
that's not consider making use of AI at
the board level
now when you look and let's briefly talk
about an organization applications of AI
you have today
I mean so many examples from credit
cards where you have ai I mean which
used to be which has been now automated
in in a massive way of how credit checks
are happening on the spot it's no longer
left to the retailer but there's a
central system which can authorize the
credit card transaction instantly or
refuse it so there has been predictive
algorithms
um being centralized and changing
the way certain tasks have been done in
an organization so I would say the
application of AI today is very much at
the front lines where it's probably
a little bit further up the chain also
is if you look at Healthcare so a
radiologist
is possibly redundant today but if you
make the radiologist redundant because a
machine can maybe possibly read
uh the image is much better it may have
repercussions of how you're going to
start organizing the whole hospital
because who's assuming now what role and
maybe the role of the nurse is going to
be upskilled because on the basis of the
machine output uh there will be
direction to the right doctor to to look
really for treatment whatever is the
reading from um from the images so I
think we need to
um
see now that AI starts first of all in a
very task specific way
but moves up and all of a sudden has
very systemic changes applying a i
at the board level
um
I don't see this
at this moment you know information
processing
will not be done at the board level with
AI tools I I doubt this at this point
when I look now specifically at free
energy governance well free energy
governance if you look at free energy
principle for me that is an artificial
active inference and the way uh
carliferson has been even applying it to
neuroimaging is a machine learning
algorithm so for me free energy
governance
is really a machine learning logic
in its entirety now when you look at
what is happening uh chat GPT is not as
smart as a lot of people think at the
end it's just a language model and uh it
it makes statistically very plausible
language it produces which it doesn't
understand itself so it poses obviously
great challenges so I think that has
been a little bit misleading having said
this
I think it's not misleading to the
extent that chat GPT is an indication
that generative intelligence automated
augmented is the future and this is
going to come and I think we will have a
hard time and humans to catch up how
fast it can evolve and the things it's
doing because it's getting better every
day because it's training on the back of
massive training knowledge now
what is happening
and that is definitely a challenge for
the board you could ask how can the
board continue fulfilling its most basic
fiduciary duty of monitoring company and
management if itself the board has no
means of understanding what the
algorithms do because algorithms can be
potentially very damaging so I do see
that there will be a safety and ethical
um a regulatory Dimension which will
probably need to be addressed at the
board level when you look at it from an
AI point of view now so that's a little
bit to the question of artificial
intelligence and free energy governance
I specific specifically have not
considered any tools at the board level
now when you look at what is artificial
intelligence really about it allows you
to separate two components which make up
a decision it's a predictive component
and it's a judgment component I think
the predictive component can be more and
more done the prediction element by
machines on the back of data but I do
think that it revalues the Judgment
component of the human
now it could be that
it's no longer really the top let's say
leaders which are best positioned to
make the Judgment component maybe people
on the front lines
now being empowered by artificially
intelligence fueled prediction models
and prediction tools can place a much
better position to make the right
judgment call so I think the impact of
artificial intelligence on the company
will be more distributed decision making
to be really more in real time
now coming back to the quote you
originally were reading out
the the most important element of that
quote is
what you see today
is that most people in leadership
positions will tell you the world has
become uncertain and it's unpredictable
and my answer to this is always first of
all uncertainty and unpredictability is
a very subjective concept it's not an
objective reality
and
your perception of uncertainty or
unpredictability is really a function of
how good is your world model how good is
your prediction model so if you're
telling me the world is uncertain you're
effectively telling me your model is not
good enough
of modeling it and in a generative
actively inferential way going step by
step forward to improve it and make the
world less uncertain
by the way I do believe also for the
pandemic was a brilliant example if you
if you had a world model which maybe
Bill Gates had that pandemics are going
to come they're going to be massive and
they're going to be Global there's no
way you're going to contain in today's
world something which started in China
it's going to stay in Wuhan but it's
going to be Global but if you think
about it it started off in 2019 November
December and people until January
February in the Western Hemisphere still
thought this was a Chinese problem
and they weren't prepared at all now
think about it some people were smart
enough and they exploited the business
opportunity by going up front into
producing a massive amount of face masks
so when all of a sudden the pandemic hit
in March April they were the ones making
fortunes because governments didn't have
the right prediction model and they
didn't have enough masks I know actually
the guys who did take advantage of this
in Switzerland and I think they made 250
million dollars or something like this
and they they because they caught really
the government naked so you see the
discrepancy even governments where you
suppose was all the resources they have
at hand all the information they have
they have bad prediction models so
your prediction model determines
how uncertain and how unpredictable the
world is
and a big problem you have today in
companies is that companies do not
Embrace uncertainty but they bury
uncertainty a book which puts this
brilliantly into perspective is from
agaval and Avi Fab
um It's called Power and prediction and
it shows very clearly how companies have
developed as aguiri said uh back in the
60s it's skilled incompetence where you
act in a way which is really contrary to
your intentions or what you really want
to achieve and what has happened is that
companies have created rules best
practices
um you could even argue that putting the
CEO in a super dominant position
controlling everything
is a form of bearing uncertainty because
you look now to one person and you say
that person is going to give me all the
answers of the world instead what we
need to do is we need to make our models
available to testing in the marketplace
in a generative inferential way
by acting and generating new data points
that make our model in a generative
fashion better and better and as a
result of it our predictions models get
better the predictions they produce get
better and the world will be perceived
as less uncertain and that's really the
essence of the quote you started off
with
so we have two elements here one is
really the the uncertainty
um element I I think we need to really
highlight is a subjective concept and
it's a question of world modeling or
prediction modeling and prediction
testing the second uh Dimension you
addressed is the one of artificial
intelligence I do think artificial
intelligence or augmented intelligence
You could argue is it really that
artificial
um uh is is is is just at the very
beginning it's going to be exponential
it's going to be faster evolving and
spreading that anybody can expect and I
do believe that
in around within 10 years
70 to 80 percent of knowledge workers
will disappear and only those people
will survive working in any organization
that can understand manage and
complement
artificial intelligence
and by the way there's so many examples
you can see how artificial intelligence
allowed in an incredible way to get rid
of
I mean millions of jobs
you know
already
and even if you think about a
radiologist has a very uh intense
training in medical education
and in the book power prediction is a
really good example I think it is in
that book other there is another great
book I recommend on the topic it's all
in on AI by devonport and mittal which
gives you a really good overview good
structure a few good case studies and
you can see that the the the the the the
the job of a radiologist
can be divided into I think roughly 35
or 38 tasks and when you look at each of
the tasks a machine can do this today so
that job is gone
yeah it's interesting the level of
synthesis so so how much of our so for
me the essence of that quote was
um cognitive offloading into systems
that can synthesize and integrate
information
um how much of that task is what is done
by Ai and I do agree with you that we
will um need to be able to work with the
AI like to understand that synthesized
synthesis and integration of information
that's provided by augmented
intelligence systems in order to be
functional in the workplace going
forward
um yeah but you see the big weaknesses
where people don't understand by the way
that quote when I recall
um it's
it's Howie you guys know Howie he wrote
a brilliant book The predictive brain
and how he is probably more structural
Bayesian guy
um but he's really brilliant in the way
he shows
it actually would
the the Bayesian brain is about is
is really you you you you
you use the world as a feedback loop
so you you can come up with any
predictions you want let the world
you know give you all the feedback you
need and that's a that's a very powerful
way of how you start a general in a
generative way
reducing uncertainty
definitely so I don't know I guess we
should maybe go on to our last set of
questions on Duality management
um so here Bijan is it only critical for
the board to understand Duality
management or do you think at every
level of the hierarchy from the front
line workers up to top tier management
to end the board does everyone need to
understand Duality management and
practice this or is it only necessarily
at the top
well I I I don't think you would explain
to anyone in the front line that you
have to engage in Duality but
um because it's a certain degree it's an
abstract con concept and I developed
Duality management really at the at the
very very top level almost
you know dynamic capabilities the
concept of dynamic capabilities
in strategy management
is defined a dynamic capability as a
non-operational capability so you say
it's a some call it also a meta
capability so it's not a task specific
capability so you would almost say when
we talk about Duality management you
move very quickly into the default mode
side of the brain and what it really is
about I I used it in the context and I
think I I said it in our last discussion
you can really reduce
everything about a company about two
Dimensions one is exploiting today's
Cash Flow and making the money that's
really the business you have and
developing the future cash flow stream
which is the exploration so you have
exploitation exploration and
there have been so many theories about
and and case studies about can you do
both at the same time how does it work
and sometimes people said oh you do
exploitation here but you create a whole
different new thing over there and you
don't mix them and sometimes they don't
mix that easily I don't think companies
have that luxury any longer and I think
exploitation focusing on today's Cash
Flow and doing something new is it
really that radical is it more
incremental is happening kind of in real
time
but it requires very strong leadership
because when you think about exploiting
today's Cash Flow is a very hardcore
operational activity so CEOs usually
immerse very very strongly in the
exploitative activity when they're
really good they can also do exploration
and they need to make sure how they
switch between the default mode which is
probably more for exploration thinking
creatively about Innovation projects and
at the same time managing
and optimizing an existing cash
generating business
my idea was
um behind Duality management to say
the board
has is actually uniquely positioned
because it's not involved in any
operational activities really of the
company the board is not involved in
running today's business
it can have a great super View
of saying where should actually maybe
the CEO be guided towards of maybe
emphasizing right now more exploitation
or exploration where people see as a
board when they analyze the business
they can see the problems that concerns
one complex second complex I have is
financial and strategic
um control and they really stand for
in-house Innovation and Innovation you
buy through by buying other companies or
certain things and
um I the view of the free and or the way
free energy governance
um
and this is how the whole section 2 is
structured you have the structural
component which is really how you
connect the top at the bottom the
cognition component is really related to
how you have a an ability to an accurate
World create a model and I always like
the Googles the Facebooks all these
companies who have created massive
businesses but they really created this
um in in a in an active way they did not
copy someone they did not do a market
research or adapt but they had a vision
of their own which I think is essential
and the third dimension are the
capabilities and the capabilities I
developed this Duality management as a
dynamic capability and dynamic
capability is really a specific meta
capability in strategy management so I
think when you look at these two
complexes how much do I focus on the
business I have how much do I focus on
the business I would like to have
tomorrow and how much of it is done
in-house and how much of this is done
possibly by buying it uh
uh forces which sometimes uh uh uh are
going against or going in line and I
think the board in its meta position
supervisory position being above the
executive leadership has a unique
position to practice this so that
indirectly answers your question I think
Duality management the more you go down
in the hierarchy of a business which
means the closer you go to the front
lines where heart tasks are being
performed the less you have a duality
management you shouldn't have a duality
management at all because people are
really focused on very specific tasks
and the further you move up and the more
you have to decide are you going to do
one of this or more of this you may find
The Duality management challenge so it
may not be just on the board but it's
certainly on the board when it comes to
exploitation exploration and financial
and strategic control
now that's a long answer I gave I hope
you could follow me
that's great thank you so much I try to
make it simple because obviously
um when you look at the very origins of
this book it was originally a
dissertation which started off uh really
in strategy management
uh and uh I'm so happy that I found it
all the way to the more neuroscientific
Dimension and we're talking the in the
in the context of the active inference
Institute
um but obviously when you talk
specifically about The Duality
management side we are really pretty
much in in Business Schools
so getting going from
um maybe a more uh
thoughtful to the more practical
um can you give an example of um
how you can reduce organizational
friction through this top-down bottom-up
hierarchical coupling like it gets very
fuzzy for me as I mean even as we're
talking about like what levels need to
understand Duality management like the
the I mean I get the communication
between the levels is key to like
organizational maintenance or like the
Persistence of a firm
um but but like Translating that into
some kind of practical terms that I
could apply at my firm for instance is
maybe a little bit more difficult so so
do you have
um any advice for us that are you know
down here in the nitty-gritty of it all
[Music]
um
so
I do think what tools you apply
that are practically of relevance is
maybe a function also of the size of the
organization so let's start with a
really big organization take a big
Insurance Company
and you have the board of an insurance
company which will be very respectable
people who have probably jobs as CEOs on
many different other companies they come
together four or five times a year they
take major decisions
um
how can such a board
better understand
independently of CEO framing as a filter
what overall is going on how can the
board make the CEO stronger to ensure
that the CEO actually is properly
connected with what's really going on
in in the in the in the in the front
lines and one concept I I like a lot I
think I've talked about it before but I
I think the concept
is a good concept to bring as an example
again because it highlights and then you
can think creatively of what other
things you can think of but they are
Shadow boards so having a group of young
high potential people who are quite far
removed from the very top
that they form aboard themselves and
have board meetings with very similar
agenda items and can discuss what should
be maybe the future agenda items and
that can serve as a tremendous source of
inspiration from the front lines to the
main board which is sitting on the very
top
and that is a wonderful way I see as
connecting uh the top and the bottom and
leading the information flow companies
which have done this is like total
energy one the French one of the biggest
energy companies in the fashion business
Prada Gucci
um and when you think about it Prada and
Gucci are obviously companies which are
living off young Talent people young
designers something edgy something new
uh because think about it in fashion
you've got to come up every season with
something which is setting a trend so
you're really dependent on being
connected to the front line and from
creative people picking up what is the
next so I like the fashion houses
because they show how important it is to
be connected to the very front lines a
big insurance company may not see it but
a big insurance company may be missing
what be the next
big thing maybe young people will be
asking for as a business model
for as an interesting Insurance market
and
um so I think that is a really good
two now let's go into small
organizations let's take the active
inference Institute as an example and
you're saying look we have this
wonderful scientific Advisory Board you
have uh a wonderful board who is
advising you uh uh and and and and and
and and guiding you
um how to make how to increase I mean
you have I think you have one purpose to
increase the impact of the active
Insurance Institute in the marketplace
and you're looking at various tools
you're looking at very various
engagement platforms our dialogue is one
of them you're reaching out through
channels to at every juncture optimize
that and I'm trying to support this as
well because I really truly believe in
in the mission of the active
interference Institute and I do believe
that it is the very beginning
of a great movement because I see that
as the future I'm absolutely convinced
of that so in that regard you're
definitely Pioneers our community is
still very small
now here's the question of how you
connect the top
which is you guys now was the was the
front line and the front line may have
really interesting
weak signals which could give you some
really inspirational input where you say
we should take it on and I think you're
doing it you're doing it with a
newsletter you're reaching out you're
obviously want to make sure people read
it they engage with this and you have
internship programs you have a number of
ways of how to bring in
really the the marketplace to challenge
you to improve you was one and only one
Mission and purpose in mind to make sure
that the products the output from the
active inference Institute has impact
represents the aspirations you have for
high quality intelligence
um that more and more people should
connect to and I think you're doing
quite a great job with the limited
resources you have by doing all these
tools creating these dialogues you are
acting actually to generate great
data points including our conversations
and the way you then package the outputs
to reach out and collect input from
people we may not know at this point who
may connect to the content and I think
this is a form
of structure in a very distributed
environment when you look at how the
active interference Institute is working
of connecting actually the top which is
you guys
the front lines are possibly people like
myself giving feedback so Frontline is
not always you know it doesn't imply is
somebody
um that's why I don't like the word
bottom
sometimes your most intelligent people
in the network may be your frontliners
giving you the right feedbacks and data
points I hope that's that answers the
question and puts a little bit more more
tangibly into your perspective
most definitely and I think uh thank you
for all the nice things you have to say
about the active inference Institute
that's always uh it's always nice to get
a compliment
um and I think that um that's it for
today unless there's any more like
burning thoughts or questions
foreign
I think the the next chapter goes a
little bit more into the corporate
governance side
I I think we've covered quite a bit uh
of this so when you I think uh next one
is three conclusion
um and um
I think 13 uh
uh chapter 13
um which is our performance and survival
as a matter of self-organization
is quite philosophical I think is a is a
topic and um
I look forward to it
and thank you so much for for also
taking interest in my work it means a
lot to an author
thank you we will see you next time okay
all the best
peace